My name's Conan Edogawa!
اسمي إيدوغاوا كونان
High school student Shinichi was forced to take a drug that shrunk him!
أُجبر طالب الثانوية كودو شينتشي على تجرّع عقار قلص جسده
Although smaller, my mind remains that of a sharp detective!
،رغم أنّي أصبحت أصغر !لا يزال عقلي عقل متحرٍّ عظيم
A review of the last episode will accompany the theme song!
ستتبع الشارة الغنائية مراجعة للحلقة السابقة
It's a big ship, but there's always only one truth!
!إنّها سفينة كبيرة، لكن الحقيقة واحدة دوماً
We were nearly stranded on an island
كدنا نعلق في جزيرة
before we were picked up by a ship that the Hatamoto family had reserved.
قبل أن تقلّنا سفينة حجزتها عائلة هاتاموتو
Including the three of us and the butler, there were only 10 people onboard.
،بمن فيهم نحن الثلاثة وخادم العائلة كان هناك عشرة أشخاص فقط
On our way back to land, Hatamoto Gozo,
في طريق عودتنا للبرّ، قُتل كبير عائلة هاتاموتو
head of the Hatamoto family, was murdered in his room.
هاتاموتو غوزو في غرفته
The main suspect was Hatamoto Takeshi,
المشتبه الرئيسي كان هاتاموتو تاكيشي
who entered the family by marrying Hatamoto Natsue.
الذي دخل العائلة بزواجه من هاتاموتو ناتسوي
He turned out to be the son of Zaiki Isao,
اتّضح أنّه ابن زايكي إيساو
who killed himself after Gozo took over his company 10 years earlier!
الذي انتحر بعدما استولى غوزو على شركته قبل 10 أعوام
Since he had a motive, everyone decided to lock Takeshi in a storeroom.
كان لديه دافعٌ كبير، فقرر الجميع احتجاز تاكيشي في مخزن
It looked like the case was closed, but there was more to come.
وبدا أنّ القضيّة حُلت، لكن كان هناك المزيد
Hatamoto Tatsuo, Akie's husband, was found dead,
وُجد زوج أكي، هاتاموتو تاتسو، مقتولاً
and Takeshi had escaped from the storeroom!
وهرب تاكيشي من المخزن
The Luxury Liner Murders, Part 2.
سلسلة جرائم قتل السفينة السياحية الفاخرة (الجزء الثاني)
Tatsuo!
...تاتسو
Akie...
...أختي
It's your fault!
!إنّها غلطتك
This never would've happened
لم يكن هذا ليحصل
if you hadn't brought Takeshi into our family!
!لو لم تُدخلي تاكيشي في العائلة
You certainly are lucky!
يا لحظّك
Now that Takeshi's killed Father,
بعدما قتل زوجك تاكيشي أبي
all of his fortune belongs to you!
!أصبحت كلّ ثروته لك
You can't be serious! I don't care about his fortune!
!لا-لا يُعقل! لا أهتم للثروة
We're still not certain that Takeshi-san is the one responsible, you know.
لم نتأكد بعد أنّ تاكيشي-سان هو القاتل
Conan-kun!
!كونان-كن
The storeroom door was unlocked when we checked it out, right?
كان قفل المخزن مفتوحاً عندما تفقدناه، صحيح؟
Yeah, that's right...
...أ-أجل
He couldn't have gotten out
لم يكن بإمكانه الخروج
unless someone unlocked it from the outside.
دون أن يفتحه أحد من الخارج
That's right...
...معك حق
There were no signs of damage on the door, either...
لم تكن هناك آثار تخريب للقفل أيضاً
So if someone did unlock it,
...إن فتحه أحدهم له
then he has an accomplice in this room!
!فيعني أنّ بينكم متواطئ
So let me get this straight.
دعوني أستوضح
At the time of Tatsuo-san's murder,
،أثناء مقتل تاتسو-سان
the three of you were alone in your private rooms,
كنتم الثلاثة بمفردكم تستريحون في غرفكم
while you two were together in your shared room.
بينما كنتما الزوجين في غرفتكما المشتركة
Well, I couldn't sleep, so I went for a little walk...
أ-أجل، لم أستطع النوم فذهبت للتمشّي
Which means that just like the first murder,
،ما يعني أنّ مثل ظروف الجريمة الأولى
aside from everyone who was with Natsue-san,
،باستثناء من كان مع كونان وناتسوي-سان
nobody here has an alibi!
!لا يملك أحد حجّة غياب
You gotta be kidding me! My husband just died!
!لا تمازحني! مات زوجي
Why am I a suspect?!
!لمَ قد يُشتبه بي؟
You're the one who's happiest to see him dead.
أنت الأكثر سروراً برؤيته ميتاً
I know that you've been seeing other men!
!أعرف أنّ هناك رجالاً آخرين في حياتك
You had a big enough reason to kill Grandfather!
!كان لديكِ دافع كبير لقتل جدّي أيضاً
You're the one who wanted his inheritance the most!
!فأنتِ أكثر من أراد إرثه
Stop it, you two! Please!
!توقفا! رجاءً
Did you draw that, Ichiro-san?
أرسمتِ هذه يا إيتشيرو-سان؟
That's Natsue-san, isn't it?
إنّها ناتسوي-سان، صحيح؟
And your son Ichiro isn't exempt either!
وابنك إيتشيرو ليس مستثنى أيضاً
Am I wrong?
ألستُ محقة؟
I'm sure he was pretty pissed
فأنا واثقة أنّ الغضب اعتراك
after Grandfather tore up his prize-winning drawing!
!بعدما مزّق جدّي رسمتك المتوّجة بجائزة
That was Father's fault-- he never recognized this boy's talent!
تلك كانت غلطة أبي! لم يعترف !بموهبة ابني أبداً
Tatsuo always made fun of you, didn't he?
كان تاتسو يسخر منك دوماً، صحيح؟
"Depressed introvert" and stuff like that...
يقول أنّك مُنغلق بائس وما شابه
No! I didn't kill him!
!كلا! لم أقتله
And the one who wanted to be free of Grandfather the most...
...وأكثر من أراد التحرّر من جدّي
...was you, Uncle Kitaro!
كان أنت يا عمّ كيتارو، أليس كذلك؟
What?
ماذا؟
Ichiro! Where are you going?
إيتشيرو، أين تذهب؟
The restroom.
دورة المياه
Will you be alright by yourself?
أستكون بخيرٍ بمفردك؟
I'll be fine. I'm not a weakling like my father!
سأكون بخير، فلستُ ضعيفاً مثلك يا أبي
Ichiro...
...إيتشيرو
Hey, Mr. Butler...
...سيّدي الخادم
Did something happen between Kitaro-san and Gozo-san?
أجرى أمرٌ ما بين كيتارو-سان والجدّ؟
Kitaro-sama has wanted to leave the Hatamoto family for a long time.
لطالما أراد كيتارو-ساما مغادرة عائلة هاتاموتو
He says he doesn't have the ambition to run the family company.
قال أنّه لا يملك طموح إدارة شركة العائلة
Gozo-sama was greatly opposed to the idea...
كان الجدّ يعارض ذلك بشدّة
But even if he wasn't against it,
،لكن حتّى لو لم يعارض
I don't think his wife Mariko-sama would have allowed it either...
لا أظنّ أن زوجته ماريكو-ساما كانت ستسمح له
Detective!
المعذرة حضرة المتحري
It's been 20 minutes, but Ichiro still isn't back from the restroom!
مضت 20 دقيقة ولم يعد إيتشيرو من دورة المياه بعد
Don't tell me Takeshi got him!
...أيمكن أنّ تاكيشي قد
Calm down! Stay where you are!
!اهدؤوا! ابقوا حيث أنتم
What?! But Ichiro isn't back yet!
!ماذا؟! لكن لم يعد إيتشيرو بعد
Ichiro!
!إيتشيرو
You mustn't leave the room, ma'am!
!لا يمكنك مغادرة الغرفة يا عمّة
Conan and Ran! Are you there?!
!ران وكونان! أأنتما هنا؟
Dad?!
!أبي
Over here!
!هنا
I'm going to the electrical room!
سأذهب لغرفة المفاتيح
You two head for the restroom!
توجّها لدورة المياه
The restrooms were this way, right?
كانت دورة المياه من هذا الاتجاه، صحيح؟
Yeah.
أجل
Wasn't that Ichiro-san's voice?!
كان ذلك صوت إيتشيرو-سان، صحيح؟
Dammit!
!تبّاً
Ichiro!
!إيتشيرو
My leg!
!ساقي
Hang in there, Ichiro!
!تماسك يا إيتشيرو
He's alright! The wound isn't deep!
إنّه بخير، الجرح سطحيّ
We need to bandage it up right away!
علينا تضميده فوراً
I'll get the first-aid kit!
سأجلب عدّة الإسعافات الأولية
Who did this to you?!
من هاجمك؟
I don't know...
لا أدري
The lights suddenly went out and then I sensed someone come in...
...انطفأت الأضواء فجأةً وشعرت بدخول أحدهم
And then they stabbed me!
!ثم طعنني
That's...
...تلك
...My knife.
سكّيني
Don't tell me you did this, Joji!
...أيمكن أنّك يا جوجي
Hold on!
!تمهلي
I was with you all in the dining room when the power went out!
كنت معكم في غرفة الطعام عندما انقطعت الكهرباء
I couldn't have done this!
!يستحيل أن فعلتُ هذا
That's true...
صـ-صحيح
There is only one person who could have done it!
شخصٌ واحد كان بإمكانه فعل هذا
Takeshi-kun!
تاكيشي-كن فقط
No, that's not necessarily the case.
كلا، ليس بالضرورة
Let Natsue-san and Ran take care of Ichiro-kun's bandage.
لنترك تضميد إيتشيرو-كن لران وناتسوي-سان
I'd like the rest of you to come to the electrical room with me.
أريدكم أن ترافقوني جميعاً لغرفة المفاتيح
Is there something here?
أيوجد شيءٌ هنا؟
Yes. Have a look for yourself.
حسنٌ، انظروا
What is this?
ما هذا؟
It's a type of timing device.
عدّة مؤقته
This one is simple enough for anyone to set up.
بسيطة بما يكفي ليصنعها أيّ أحد
You attach a heavy weight to the breaker, balance it around a fulcrum,
،تربط وزناً ثقيلاً بالقاطع ولوحة ارتكاز
and then put a candle in the middle.
ثمّ تضع شمعةً بينهما
After enough time passes, the rope burns apart,
بعد مضيّ وقتٍ كافٍ سيحترق الحبل
which causes the weight to pull down on the breaker.
فيسقط الوزن ويسحب القاطع
Judging from how much of the candle has melted,
،بالنظر إلى الكمية الذائبة من الشمعة
this was all set up quite a while ago.
يمكن القول أنها وُضعت قبل فترة
In other words, any one of you could be responsible for the power outage.
مما يعني يمكن أن أيّ منكم قد يكون مسؤولاً عن قطع الكهرباء
At any rate, I'll take the responsibility of finding Takeshi-san.
بأيّ حال، سأتحمل مسؤولية إيجاد تاكيشي-سان
Until I do, I don't want any of you to take a step out of the dining room!
لا أريدكم أن تخرجوا من غرفة الطعام أبداً حتى أفعل
Does it hurt, Ichiro?!
أتشعر بألم يا إيتشيرو؟
Damn it...
تباً
I can't believe we've looked this hard but still haven't found him!
بحثنا في كلّ مكان ولم نجده
Then maybe he's not on the ship anymore?
لعلّه ليس على متن السفينة
I don't think we've searched everywhere yet...
لا أظننا بحثنا في كلّ مكان
Like everyone's rooms!
كغرف أفراد العائلة
He's not in Kitaro-san's room.
ليس في غرفة الزوجين كيتارو
These two seem to have rather different personalities.
يبدو أنّ شخصية هذين الاثنين متناقضة
Is their marriage holding up well?
هل زواجهما على ما يرام؟
Yes. They're both cousins, and although it may not look like it,
،أجل، إنّهما قريبان. وبخلاف ما يبدو عليهما
they've been good friends since they were little.
فهما صديقان مقرّبان مذ صغرهما
They're cousins and they're married?!
!قريبان ومتزوّجان؟
Yes. Come to think of it,
صحيح، وفقما أذكر
Gozo-sama was extremely opposed to them, too.
كان السيّد غوزو معارضاً بشدة أيضاً
"Them, too"?
أيضاً"؟"
Doesn't look like he's in Joji-san's room, either.
يبدو أنّه ليس في غرفة جوجي-سان أيضاً
Hey, is this his knife case?
أهذه حقيبة السكاكين خاصته؟
What?!
!ماذا؟
Two of his knives are missing!
!سـ-سكّينتان مفقودتان
What does it mean?
ما معنى هذا؟
One knife we found right after Ichiro-kun was attacked,
وجدنا واحدة بعدما طُعن إيتشيرو-كن
but where's the other one?
لكن أين الأخرى؟
This must be Ichiro-san's room!
لا بدّ أنّها غرفة إيتشيرو-سان
See? These are his drawings!
!فهذه رسماته
That's no reason to enter the room carelessly!
لا يعني هذا أن تدخلي غرفته بلا حذر
Takeshi-kun could be hiding in here with a weapon!
قد يكون تاكيشي-كن مختبئاً هنا بسلاح
Wow, he's really good!
رسمه متقنٌ حقاً
Who knows, maybe there's a drawing of the murder scene here!
قد نجد رسمةً لمسرح الجريمة
Yeah, right.
كأنّ ذلك سيحصل
Hey now, don't touch those!
لا تعبثي بها
Alright.
حسناً
He's not in here, either.
ليس هنا إذاً
It would seem not.
يبدو ذلك
Hey, what's this?
ما هذا؟
Charcoal. You use it for rough sketches.
فحم، تستعمله للرسم المبدئي
Then what's this?
ما هذا إذاً؟
Hey, get the lead out. We're moving on.
يكفي مماطلة، سنغادر
Coming!
حسناً
It's an ordinary eraser.
إنّها مسّاحة عادية
I see...
...هكذا إذاً
He wasn't in our rooms or in Natsue-san's room.
لم يكن في غرفتنا أو غرفة ناتسوي-سان
All that's left is Akie-san's room here...
تبقّت غرفة أكي-سان هنا فقط
I guess he's not on the ship anymore...
لعلّه لم يعد على متن السفينة بعد
Did you find something?
أوجدت شيئاً؟
No! Nothing at all!
!كلا! لا شيء
Oh well.
حسنٌ، فعلنا ما باستطاعتنا
Let's return to the dining room for now.
لنرجع لغرفة الطعام
Hey, Mr. Butler.
أخبرني، سيّدي الخادم
Do you know if...?
...أيمكن
Did that ever happen?
أحصل ذلك قبلاً؟
How did you find out? Only Gozo-sama and I know about that!
!كيف عرفت؟! فقط غوزو-ساما وأنا نعرف
The first incident, in which Mr. Gozo was killed...
الحادثة الأولى التي قُتل فيها السيّد غوزو
The bread found near the body, and the location of the murder weapon...
،كانت هناك كسرة الخبز قرب الجثّة كما موقع سلاح الجريمة
The second incident, in which Tatsuo-san was killed...
...والحادثة الثانية التي قُتل فيها تاتسو-سان
The splash and thud sounds I heard at the time of the murder...
كان هناك صوت السقوط في الماء والارتطام الذي سمعته وقت الجريمة
The person who unlocked the storeroom door...
...والشخص الذي فتح قفل المخزن
And then the third incident, in which Ichiro-san was stabbed in the dark...
ثمّ الحادثة الثالثة حيث طُعن إيتشيرو-سان في الظلام
Each of these mysteries is connected by a single thread!
!كلّ هذه الألغاز مربوطة بخيط
Hey, come here a sec!
!عمّي! تعال قليلاً
What is it?
ماذا هناك؟
Did you find something?
أوجدت شيئاً؟
Sorry, old man!
آسف يا عمّ
Huh? Where's Dad?
ماذا؟ وأبي؟
He has something important to say,
لديه كلامٌ مهم ليقوله
so he wants everyone to come to Akie-san's room in 10 minutes.
يطلب من الجميع القدوم لغرفة أكي-سان في غضون 10 دقائق
Something important to say?
كلام مهم
Tell the others!
!نعتمد عليك
Come on! Come on!
!بسرعة! بسرعة! بسرعة
The old man's voice is #59...
...صوت العمّ رقم 59
You know who did it?!
!عرفت هويّة المجرم؟
Yes. Someone on this ship was responsible for all three incidents.
أجل، الشخص المسؤول عن الحوادث الثلاث على متن السفينة
Who is it?!
!مـ-من كان؟
It's obviously him!
!هو حتماً
It was Takeshi's doing!
!كان فعل تاكيشي
Now, now, just calm down...
...لا تعجلوا
Before I reveal the killer's name, let us look at the incidents again.
لنراجع الحوادث قبل أن أكشف اسم القاتل
First was Incident #1, in which Mr. Gozo was murdered in his room,
الحادثة الأولى هي حيث قُتل السيّد غوزو في غرفته
which had been locked from the inside.
المقفلة من الداخل
From the fact that there was blood on the doorframe,
وجود دماء على إطار مدخل الباب
Mr. Gozo likely escaped back into his room after he was stabbed outside.
يعني أنّ السيّد غوزو هرب لغرفته بعدما طُعن في الخارج
He then locked the door, but fell lifeless soon after.
ثمّ أقفل الباب ولفظ آخر أنفاسه
We later found a flower on the ground in front of the room!
ووجدنا لاحقاً زهرةً أمام باب الغرفة
Yeah! Takeshi was wearing it!
!أجل، كان تاكيشي يضعها
That means he did it!
!مما يعني أنّه الفاعل
But there is one strange detail.
لكن هناك أمرٌ محير
Even though Mr. Gozo was stabbed outside his room,
،رغم أنّ السيد غوزو طُعن خارج غرفته
there were no blood marks in the hallway.
لم تكن هناك آثار دماء في الردهة
Are you sure the killer didn't wipe it up
لأنّ القاتل مسحها كي يؤخر
to delay us from discovering the corpse?
اكتشاف الجثّة غالباً
I'm not refuting that fact--
لا أدحض تلك الحقيقة
I'm just saying that the flower fell after the blood was wiped up!
ما أقصده هو أنّ الزهرة سقطت بعدما مُسح الدم
I can understand if the killer accidentally dropped it
يمكن فهم سقوطها من القاتل دون أن ينتبه
while stabbing the victim and then escaping...
أثناء طعنه للضحية وهربه
But the killer meticulously wiped up the blood.
لكنّ القاتل مسح الدم بعناية
By leaving the flower there, everyone would've noticed it.
كان يُفترض أن ينتبه للزهرة لو كانت على الأرض وقتها
Especially if it was dropped during the middle of cleaning.
خصوصاً لو سقطت وهو يمسح
In other words, the killer purposely left the flower on the ground
مما يعني أنّ القاتل تعمد رمي الزهرة على الأرض
in order to make Takeshi-san look guilty.
كي يُلفق التهمة بتاكيشي-سان
Next is Incident #2, in which Tatsuo-san was murdered on the deck.
وفي الحادثة الثانية، تاتسو-سان الذي قُتل على سطح السفينة
Unlike the first incident with its flower
بخلاف الحادثة الأولى بالزهرة
and the third incident with its fancy set-up,
والحادثة الثالثة بعدّة القاطع
this incident lacked any sort of artificiality.
لم يكن هناك أيّ تكلّف فيها
If these were all indeed done by the same person,
،لو كان مرتكبها الشخص نفسه حقاً
my guess is that the 2nd murder was an unplanned one.
فأرجّح أنّ الجريمة الثانية وقعت بلا تخطيط سابق
Now then, why was Tatsuo-san murdered?
إذاً، نسأل لمَ قُتل تاتسو-سان؟
The answer to that question is in this case.
الإجابة نجدها في هذه الحقيبة
That's my knife case!
!إ-إنها حقيبة سكاكيني
Have a look. Two knives are missing.
أمعنوا النظر، هناك سكّينتان ناقصتان
We found one of them at the scene of Incident #3,
وجدنا إحداهما مكان الحادثة الثالثة
but where did the other one go?
لكن أين ذهبت الأخرى؟
The main point here is in the two sounds that Conan heard.
المحور هنا هما الصوتان اللذان سمعهما كونان
The thud was likely the sound of the killer striking Tatsuo-san,
كان الارتطام صوت ضرب القاتل لتاتسو-سان
but what was the splash that came before it?
لكن ما كانت قصّة صوت السقوط في الماء بعده؟
Here's what I'm thinking--
...إليكم رأيي
the splash sound was the other knife from this case.
كان ذلك صوت رمي السكّين الأخرى الناقصة من الحقيبة
If Tatsuo-san just happened to see it thrown overboard,
،لو صادف أن رأى تاتسو-سان ذلك
the killer could have killed him to keep things quiet.
وقتله الفاعل كي يكتم سرّه
That would make the most sense.
ستتصل النقاط
But Takeshi vanished from the storeroom after the 2nd incident!
لكنّ تاكيشي اختفى من المخزن !بعد الحادثة الثانية
Yeah! Takeshi is the most suspicious here!
!صحيح! تاكيشي هو الأكثر إثارةً للشبهة
No, that storeroom door was locked from the outside.
كلا، كان ذاك المخزن مقفلاً من الخارج
Escape would have been impossible
يستحيل الخروج دون أن يفتح أحدٌ لك
unless someone unlocked it for him!
من الخارج
Who was it then?!
من كان إذاً؟
Who opened it?!
من فتحه؟
The killer.
القاتل
Tatsuo-san's murder wasn't part of the killer's plan,
كان قتل تاتسو-سان خارج خطّته الأصلية
and it took place while Takeshi-san was locked up.
ووقع ذلك أثناء احتجاز تاكيشي-سان
The killer worked so hard to make Takeshi-san look guilty,
عانى القاتل كي يُلفق التهمة بتاكيشي-سان
but this 2nd murder would do just the opposite and prove his innocence.
وكانت هذه الجريمة الثانية لتعكس الأمور وتثبت براءته
So the killer unlocked the door.
لذا فتح القاتل قفل الباب
This was done to make it look like Takeshi-san
فعلها كي يوهم أنّ تاكيشي-سان
had the ability to murder Tatsuo-san, as well.
قادر على ارتكاب الجريمة الثانية
Then why did Takeshi-san run away?!
!لمَ هرب تاكيشي إذاً؟
Yeah! We still haven't found him!
!صحيح! لم نجده بعد
Let's have him explain that himself.
لنوجّه ذلك له
Takeshi-san. Why don't you stop hiding and come out?
تاكيشي-سان، لمَ لا تتوقف عن الاختباء وتخرج؟
He's in this room?!
!إنّه في هذه الغرفة؟
Takeshi-san!
!تاكيشي-سان
Now then, tell us what happened when you escaped from the storeroom.
هيّا، أخبرنا بما حصل عندما غادرت المخزن
I thought something happened to Natsue...
ظننتُ أنّ أمراً ما حلّ بناتسوي
I couldn't stand around doing nothing,
،لم أستطع البقاء ساكناً
and as I was pounding on the door, it suddenly unlocked.
،وعندما نهضتُ للضرب على الباب وجدتُ القفل مفتوحاً
I ran out of there!
فهربت
And then when I went up to the deck...
...وعندما خرجت لسطح السفينة
Takeshi did it again!
!إنّه تاكيشي! فعلها مجدداً
Tatsuo!
!تاتسو
Realizing that I would be blamed again,
أدركتُ أن التهمة ستُوجه لي مجدداً
I ran into Akie-san's room, whose door just happened to be open.
فدخلت غرفة أكي-سان التي كان بابها مفتوحاً
After that, I stayed inside the closet the entire time.
وبقيت مختبئاً داخل الخزانة
So the person who stabbed Ichiro-san during Incident #3
أي أنّ الشخص الذي طعن إيتشيرو-كن في الحادثة الثالثة
wasn't him either...
...لم يكن أنت أيضاً
Who was it?!
!من كان؟
Why would they do something this horrible to Ichiro?!
!لمَ قد يؤذي إيتشيرو بهذه الفظاعة؟
Because the killer made a big mistake.
لأنّ القاتل ارتكب خطأً فادحاً
Mistake?
خطأ؟
Yes. Unlocking the storeroom door.
أجل، فتح قفل باب المخزن
The killer had managed to frame Takeshi-san,
تمكن القاتل من إلفاق التهمة بتاكيشي-سان بإتقان
but now it looked like he had an accomplice who had let him out!
لكن بدا الآن أنّ هناك متعاوناً أخرجه
It wasn't until then that anyone started to suspect the real killer!
لم يشكّ أحد بهوية القاتل الحقيقي حتى حينها
Flustered, the murderer came up with a scheme
وفي هلعه فكّر القاتل بخطة عاجلة
to avoid any further suspicion...
لإزالة أيّ شبهات تحيطه
Incident #3, in which Ichiro-san was attacked in the restroom.
وكانت الحادثة الثالثة حيث طُعن إيتشيرو-سان في دورة المياه
But it was in this incident that the killer dug his own grave.
لكنها كانت الحادثة التي أوقعت القاتل في قبره
In the darkness, the killer shouldn't have been able to see Ichiro-kun.
يُفترض أنّ القاتل لم يستطع رؤية إيتشيرو-كن في الظلام
Even so, he was clearly able to see Ichiro-kun well enough to stab him.
مع ذلك تمكن من تحديده بدقة وطعنه
How could that be?
كيف يُعقل ذلك؟
Moreover, the weapon was found lying at the scene of the crime.
بالإضافة، هناك السلاح الذي وجدناه في مسرح الحادثة
Unlike the first two incidents, the attacker didn't leave with the weapon!
بخلاف أوّل جريمتين، لم يترك الفاعل السلاح
No, the attacker couldn't have left with it.
كلا، لم يستطع إلّا أن يتركه
After all, he couldn't go anywhere with his injured leg.
فساقه كانت مصابة ولا يمكنه الحركة
You don't mean to say--
...إ-إذاً
That's right.
صحيح
The person who stabbed him... was Ichiro-kun himself!
!إيتشيرو-كن طعن نفسه بنفسه
And the one who killed Mr. Gozo and Tatsuo-san...
ومن قتل السيّد غوزو وتاتسو-سان
...was you, Ichiro-kun!
كان أنت... يا إيتشيرو-كن
Ichiro...
...إيتشيرو
The reason you put the lights out
سبب إطفائك للأضواء
was because you didn't want to identify your attacker.
هو لأنّك لم ترد أن ترد تحديد هويّة مُهاجمك
If you said it was Takeshi-san and then he was found innocent later,
لو قلتَ أنّه تاكيشي-سان ثمّ ثبتت براءته
then all the suspicion would fall onto you.
فستتحول الشبهة نحوك
This is all conjecture!
!كلها افتراضات
Do you have any evidence that Ichiro's the murderer?!
!ألديك دليل أنّ إيتشيرو كان القاتل؟
This is the evidence.
هذا هو الدليل
The piece of bread that was found near Mr. Gozo's body.
كسرة الخبز التي وجدناها قرب جثّة السيد غوزو
A piece of bread?
كسرة خبز؟
Ichiro-san is an art student.
إيتشيرو-كن طالب فنون
And right before Mr. Gozo was murdered,
،وقبل قتل السيّد غوزو
he was drawing a picture on the deck.
كان يرسم على سطح السفينة
Bread pieces are sometimes used as erasers for charcoal sketches,
تُستعمل كسرات الخبز لمسح رسمات الفحم أحياناً
and I hear that these pieces often fall into artists' cuffs.
وسمعتُ أنّها تدخل فتحات أكمام الرسامين عادةً
When he stabbed Mr. Gozo, that piece of bread fell out of his cuff.
عندما طعن السيّد غوزو، سقطت كسرة الخبز من كمّ إيتشيرو-كن
It fell onto Mr. Gozo's blood, you see.
وعلى دمّ السيد غوزو
What's more, this bread piece has a tiny bit of charcoal on it.
كما أنّ كسرة الخبز هذه تحوي نسبة صغيرة من الفحم
There is no doubt that it was Ichiro-kun who dropped it!
لا ريب أنّها سقطت من إيتشيرو-كن
But he has no motive!
!لكن لا دافع لديه
Ichiro had no reason to kill Father!
!لا سبب ليقتل إيتشيرو أبي
I, myself, couldn't tell what his motive was until the very end.
لم أستطع معرفة دافعه حتى النهاية
Until I saw something in his room, that is.
إلى أن رأيتُ شيئاً في غرفة إيتشيرو-كن
Something in his room?!
شيء في غرفته؟
This.
هذا
This is Ichiro-kun's motive for killing Mr. Gozo.
هذا دافع إيتشيرو-كن لقتل السيّد غوزو
How is a picture his motive?
لمَ الرسمة هي دافعه؟
The answer is in the drawing itself.
الإجابة في الرسمة نفسها
I don't see how...
...لا أفهم
Stop it...
...توقفي
Stop it!
!توقفي
Wait! All these drawings are of Natsue!
!لحظة، هذه كلّها رسمات لناتسوي
Ichiro! Don't tell me you--
...إ-إيتشيرو، أيمكن أنّك
That's right.
صحيح
Ichiro-kun was in love with Natsue-san.
كان إيتشيرو-كن واقعاً في حُب ناتسوي-سان
Ichiro-san...
...إيتشيرو-سان
I heard from Suzuki-san, the butler.
سمعتُ من الخادم سوزوكي-سان
Unable to reveal your feelings to Natsue-san,
،عاجزاً عن البوح بمشاعرك لناتسوي-سان
you went to Mr. Gozo and--
...ذهبت للسيّد غوزو و
It's true! I asked him to let me marry Natsue-san!
!صحيح! طلبتُ منه الزواج بناتسوي-سان
But he wouldn't hear me out!
لكنه رفض الإصغاء لي
He refused to give his beloved Natsue-san to someone like me!
قال أنّه لن يرمي ناتسوي الغالية بين أحضان شخصٍ مثلي
And soon after that, almost as if to spite me,
وبفترة وجيزة بعدها كما لو كانت نكايةً بي
he announced that Natsue-san was going to marry Takeshi-san!
!أعلن أن ناتسوي-سان ستتزوج من تاكيشي-سان
And then when he yelled at me yesterday
ثمّ صرخ بي بالأمس عندما
while I was on the deck, drawing Natsue-san...
كنتُ على سطح السفينة أرسم ناتسوي-سان
Tell him to give up his hopeless dream!
!أخبره أن ييأس من حلمه المستحيل
I couldn't forgive them!
لم أستطع مسامحتهما
Not my grandfather, who refused to let me marry Natsue-san...
جدّي الذي رفض تزويجي بناتسوي-سان
Nor Takeshi-san, who stole my Natsue-san away from me!
وتاكيشي-سان الذي سرق !ناتسوي-سان مني! لم أستطع
Takeshi-san.
تاكيشي-سان
Do you still feel the same way toward my grandfather and us?
لا تزال تكنّ الضغينة نحو عائلتنا وجدّي؟
I am the son of Zaiki Isao,
أنا ابن زايكي إيساو الذي انتحر
who committed suicide after the Hatamoto Group took over his company.
بعدما استولت مجموعة هاتاموتو على شركته بالفعل
And it's true that I got close to you because I hated your grandfather.
تقرّبتُ منك لأنّي أبغضت جدّك صدقاً
But ever since I met you...
...لكن مُذ التقيتك
The tragedy was caused by a shy young man
المأساة سبّبها شابٌ خجول
who was unable to put his secret thoughts into words...
عجز عن التعبير عن مشاعره الخفية بكلمات
The ship is nearing Tokyo...
...تقترب السفينة من طوكيو
...while being bathed by the red sunset that is the sadness and despair
ويكسوها غروب الشمس الأحمر الذي يمثّل حزن ويأس
of Ichiro-san and the entire Hatamoto family.
إيتشيرو-سان وعائلة هاتاموتو
She has...
...تعاني
...Amnesia?!
فقدان ذاكرة؟
That's him!
...ذاك الرجل
Why is the man from the racetrack
لمَ يستهدف ذاك الرجل من مضمار السباق
after Maya-san?!
!مايا-سان؟
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
The Case of the Mysterious Woman with Amnesia.
قضيّة المرأة فاقدة الذاكرة الغامضة
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Brooch.
دبّوس زينة